rpgfan.com 2019-09-09

# RPGFan - Legal Info and Privacy Policy

All games, game titles, characters, music, pictures, and related media contained within this online publication are copyright and trademarks of their respective companies and are used with permission. Reproduction of works published on [http://www.rpgfan.com](http://www.rpgfan.com/) in whole or in part without written permission by the publisher is strictly prohibited. All section titles, characters, and related indicia contained within this publication are copyright and trademarks of RPGFan, All Rights Reserved. All HTML, JavaScript, CSS, other custom code, graphics and logo are property of RPGFan unless otherwise noted. RPGFan is owned by RPGFan Media, LLC, a Minnesota Limited Liability Company.

_This policy was updated as of May 25, 2018 to reflect new data privacy laws such as GDPR, to better explain our data collection and retention policies, and exactly what information is collected and how it is used._

Please note that RPGFan does not currently offer the ability to sign up as a member of the site itself (aside from the forums), but will in the future. Only basic information will be required to register, with any additional personal information submitted at your own discretion. If needed, this page will be updated in the future to reflect any changes.

By using this site, you agree to the Privacy Policy of RPGFan. If you do not agree to the Policy, please do not use this site. RPGFan reviews its privacy policy periodically and reserves the right, at its discretion, to modify or remove portions of this policy at any time. You should check this page regularly so that you are up to date with any changes. If you want to communicate with us about our policy, please e-mail us via our staff page.

RPGFan, which operates the Internet site located at www.rpgfan.com, recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of personally identifiable information collected about visitors to our sites. As a general policy, no personally identifiable information, such as your name, address or email address, is automatically collected from visitors to our sites. Personally identifiable information about visitors to our sites is collected only when knowingly and voluntarily submitted. We may collect certain non-personal information to optimize our Web pages for your computer (i.e., the identity of your Internet browser, the type of operating system you use, your IP address and the domain name of your Internet service provider). We may use such non-personal information for internal purposes, including but not limited to improving the content of our sites.

In those instances when we do collect personally identifiable information, the following policies apply:

RPGFan will notify you when we are collecting personally identifiable information about you and we will tell you how we intend to use it. For example, we may need to collect such information if you were to participate in an online contest with deliverable rewards.

Sometimes RPGFan engages in activities with business partners with whom personal information is jointly collected or shared. We will make it clear at the time of collection who is asking for and/or sharing your information. In situations where your information will be shared, it is recommended that you also review the privacy policy of our business partner. This rule generally applies solely to partners and/or sponsors of online contests.

Personally identifiable information that you submit to our site is used only for the purpose for which it is submitted unless we disclose other uses in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection. This information may include:

  * Information you provide by signing up to our forums, such as username, email address, and password.
  * As a user of our forums, as outlined in the registration agreement, your IP address is recorded for each post in the event that you need to be banned from this forum or your ISP contacted. This will only happen in the event of a major violation of this agreement. This information is only used for moderation and disciplinary action if needed, and only available to forum administrators and moderators.
  * RPGFan may use personally identifiable information in aggregate form — such as device type, browser, OS, and screen resolution — to make our sites better and more responsive to the needs of our visitors. This statistical compilation and analysis of information may also be used by RPGFan or provided to others, in aggregate, for marketing, advertising or research purposes. You can choose to opt out of being included in Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * Information you choose to submit to RPGFan in the form of emails, comments, messages.
  * Information you choose to submit to RPGFan as part of a contest, giveaway, newsletter, or promotional campaign. This information is used only for the purpose for which it is submitted unless we disclose other uses in this Privacy Policy or at the time of collection.

Some information you submit to us is shared publicly, and some isn't. This is what is shared publicly:

  * Your forum account username, registration date, and any posts you have made.
  * Any additional forum profile information you add to your profile and choose to make available to the public. Most profile fields are optional and can either be left blank or you can choose to hide them from public view.

Information that is not shared publicly:

  * Your forum password.
  * Your IP address.
  * Private forum profile information.
  * Private communications you send to us, via email, our forums, Discord, social media, or other means are not shared publicly, unless you grant us explicit permission to do so.

Information that may be shared to protect RPGFan and comply with the law:

  * Personal information may be disclosed in special situations where RPGFan has reason to believe that doing so is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against anyone damaging, injuring, or interfering (intentionally or unintentionally) with RPGFan's rights, property, users, or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities. Also, RPGFan may reveal information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

We retain your forum profile information as long as your account is active, and will continue to do so unless you choose to close your account and request that we delete it.

Email communications are retained only for purposes such as to continue dialog, or as reference for internal informational purposes, and will only be kept as long as needed.

RPGFan is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of our business partners. 

RPGFan may include links to external websites or services with their own privacy policies and practices. By following a link to another website or service, you are subject to that website or service's terms and data processing policies.

RPGFan may use reputable third parties to manage activities available on our sites. These parties may have access to personally identifiable information submitted by visitors who participate in those activities. Similarly, we may contract with third parties to handle the fulfillment of subscriptions or requests for information you submit to our sites, such as sending you a newsletter. In most instances, RPGFan instructs these third parties to use personally identifiable information only for the specific purpose for which it is collected, and not to sell, market or transfer such information to other entities. If RPGFan obtains personal information that has been collected from you by a third party, including our business partners, this Privacy Policy nonetheless governs RPGFan use of that information.

Please remember that any information posted on message boards becomes public information. You should use caution when sharing information as any of it can be collected and used by people you may not know. Users under the age of 18 should be particularly careful not to divulge any personal information. While RPGFan strives to protect and respect your privacy, we can not guarantee the security of any information you disclose in a message board and you do so at your own risk.

In the future, RPGFan may offer options to subscribe to updates via the site or a newsletter. These or any other similar services will be offered only on an opt-in basis. If you choose to sign up, but at any time after submitting your personal information to our sites you would no longer like to receive information from us, simply follow the "unsubscribe" directions at the end of any email communication you receive.

RPGFan abides by COPPA and does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.

RPGFan maintains appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of personally identifiable information submitted to our sites, and periodically reviews and updates its security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure. Although RPGFan strives to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warranty the security of any information you may transmit to us or from our online products and services. This is done so at your own risk. Once we do receive your transmission, however, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. When credit card information is transmitted, industry standard encryption is used. 

Cookies are data that a website transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies, which are an industry standard used by most websites, including those operated by RPGFan, can facilitate a user's ongoing access to and use of a site. They allow us to track usage patterns and to compile data that can help us improve our content and target advertising. RPGFan does not save passwords or credit card information within Cookies, nor are our Cookies programs that can cause damage to a user's systems or files. If you do not want information collected through the use of Cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to deny or accept the Cookie feature. But you should note that Cookies may be necessary to provide you with features such as merchandise transactions or registered services.

By making purchases via affiliate links on RPGFan, including Amazon (for game reviews), CDJapan, Play-Asia, and others (for music reviews), RPGFan may earn a small share of each sale. Any money earned via sales is put back into the costs of running the site or to make improvements.

RPGFan earns revenue on Twitch from subscriptions, bits, and donations. Any revenue earned, like with affiliate links, is put towards the costs of running the site or to make improvements.

By subscribing to our Twitch channel, you're choosing to provide us with the following information:

  * Your public Twitch username.
  * The subscription tier you purchased and its value (i.e. $4.99, $9.99)

As a channel creator, Twitch allows us the option to download a CSV file of subscribers. This file contains only the information listed below, and will never be viewed or shared with any person or entity outside of RPGFan:

  * Your public Twitch username.
  * The date on which you subscribed to our channel.
  * The subscription tier you purchased and its value (i.e. $4.99, $9.99)
  * A true/false field that indicates whether or not you are "paying" or not. Those who use their free Twitch Prime subscription are listed as "false."

All payment and personal information on your Twitch and Amazon (which owns Twitch) accounts is not accessible by us. Specifically, we do **not** have access to your:

  * Twitch or Amazon email address, password, or other login information.
  * Credit card, PayPal, or any other payment information.
  * Any form of information on your payment, purchase, or browsing history on Twitch, Amazon, or any other website.
  * As a channel creator, Twitch allows us the option to send emails to our subscribers through the Twitch dashboard, but we do not have access to your actual email address or other contact information.
